ELIZABETH MADRID LUNA

Greater DFW Area | (630) 414-0115

elizabeth.ma luna@yahoo.com | linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-madrid-luna/

PROFILE

Software Developer that can adapt to the constant churn in the technological world we live in today. Experienced developer with 17+ years as a team player with leadership experience with several features under my belt also provided continued support of features well after being released to the customer. Able to communicate well with fellow developers and key stakeholders to help problem solve and motivate team members to complete projects on time. Willing to tackle anything new with the ability to come up to speed quickly.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C | C++ | HTML | JavaScript | CSS | XML | Perl | PHP | Bash scripting | SQL |

C# | AngularJS | ColdFusion | Java | Python | jQuery |

Operating Systems: Unix | Windows | Linux

Other: Microsoft Excel | Project Management | SharePoint | Wiki | Confluence | JIRA |

CMS | CCMS | SSMS | Visual Code | Visual Studio |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOKIA

(formerly Alcatel-Lucent)

(formerly Lucent Technologies)

Jan 2016 – Sept 2018

Dec 2006 – Jan 2016

Jan 2001 – Dec 2006

Web Developer (2016 – 2018)

Dedicated team who maintained and enhanced front-end and back-end project functionality utilized by internal and external customers. Involved in all stages of the product life- cycle and closely interacted with test, architecture, and support teams.

- Worked in partnership with the customer support team to familiarize self with project functionality and provided support within the first week of employment.
- Teamed up with an excellent project team, together received company <u>Recognition of Excellence Award</u> for going beyond the call of duty, providing 24x7 customer support on initial roll-out/installation of new hardware, and aided in-house customer support.
- Closely worked with the Project Manager to help maintain backlog and daily status reports to help support the team and keep the project on track.
- Provided deliverables to customers inside a four-week turnaround timeframe which included corrections and enhancements using value-based prioritization.

Software Developer (2001 – 2014)

Assigned to projects with both national and international partners to complete feature development tasks utilizing Agile Methodology. Software Lead for ~5 software features in CDMA, 3G, and LTE working all the product life-cycle states.

- Implemented code and executed developer tests.
- Arranged remote and face-to-face meetings to increase teamwork.
- Scrum master experience, supported team with impediments and project status.
- Participated in a team project to retrofit and upgrade features; maintained system downtime to <60 seconds andworked on software upgrade completion time reduction by 10%.
- Assisted Architecture in revising a 'pay-as-you-grow' feature to provide an unlimited allowance for telecommunication services. Profit margins increased directly as a result.
- Relayed project directives as the contact for the customer team to support initial customer roll-out for multiple features.

ELIZABETH MADRID LUNA

(630) 414-0115 | elizabeth.ma | luna@yahoo.com | | Page 2

Software Developer (Continued)

- Directed on-call support access to customer site for troubleshooting, which led to quicker resolutions/workarounds on ~70% reported issues.
- Maintained simulated development labs which aided in co-worker task completion.
- Led root cause analysis discussion and assisted in implementing improvements and preventative actions.
- Involved in code cleanup activity which led to a 10% code reduction.
- Facilitated lunch-and-learn sessions to promote knowledge sharing to boost team unity for the company's mission and success.
- Mentored interns and peers by assisting with source control development, code implementation and verification.
- Created training documents to simplify maneuvering work guidelines and required tools used within the company.

Project Management (2014-2016)

Software developer with project management experience, which is beneficial in realizing scheduling and communicating with development teams. LTE Release Leader for US team of 100 people; coordinated ~15 features working closely with leaders from multiple regions.

- Communicated feature status to upper management.
- Interacted with management teams to appropriate resources needed for positive release completion.
- Navigated successfully with development peers to obtain status, coordination, and completion of tasks, resulted in ~92% feature code delivered as scheduled.
- Mitigated issues allowing development teams to average 17-day ticket turnaround onissues found during in-house testing and customer issues.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at El Paso (UTEP)
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Collin College

Associates in Web and Mobile Development (expected May 2021)

CERTIFICATES

Full-Stack Web Developer- Collin College (expected May 2021)
Front-End Web Developer- Collin College (expected May 2021)
Mobile Application Developer- Collin College (expected May 2021)